* Accessibility

* Choose Language

Follow us:

*   
    Search
*   
    Menu
*   
    Social
*   
    Languages
*   
    Accessibility

Visiting Info

**Opening Hours:**

Sunday to Thursday: ‬09:00-17:00

Fridays and Holiday eves: ‬09:00-14:00

Yad Vashem is closed on Saturdays and all Jewish Holidays.

Entrance to the Holocaust History Museum is not permitted for children under the age of 10. Babies in strollers or carriers will not be permitted to enter.

**Drive to Yad Vashem:**

1. [Home](https://www.yadvashem.org/)
2. Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
==============

### Introduction

Thank you for visiting the internet site of Yad Vashem – The Holocaust Martyrs’ and Heroes’ Remembrance Authority (hereinafter: “**Yad Vashem**”). This Privacy Policy applies to all the services offered by Yad Vashem (hereinafter: the “**Services**”), including those offered on the site [https://www.yadvashem.org](https://www.yadvashem.org/) and sub-domains administered and operated by Yad Vashem (hereinafter: the “**Site**”).

Yad Vashem is committed to protecting your personal information and your privacy.  Accordingly, we act with transparency with regard to all matters involving the collection and use of your personal information.  It is important to us that you have, at all times, all the information you require in order to make an informed decision about Yad Vashem’s use of your personal information.

Our Privacy Policy is intended to provide you with a broad and clear picture, to the extent possible, with respect to the personal information we collect, the manner in which we use and protect your personal information, and your privacy rights.

The [Terms of Use](https://www.yadvashem.org/terms-and-conditions.html), which apply alongside this Privacy Policy, also govern your use of the Site.

### Collection of Personal Information and Purposes of Usage

Yad Vashem collects personal information which you knowingly choose to provide to us, as well as which is directly required for use of the Site and/or for provision of Services.  It is important to emphasize that you are not obligated to provide any personal information to Yad Vashem. However, in certain circumstances, withholding personal information may prevent use of the Site and/or provision of certain Services.

Personal information collected by Yad Vashem is used in accordance with this Privacy Policy and/or in accordance with law, and as required in order to enable your use of the Site and/or Services. Yad Vashem collects personal data for the purpose of providing the Services and/or advancing its objectives (hereinafter: the “**Purposes**”), which includes the following:

* **Visiting Yad Vashem facilities and/or Participation in Educational and/or Cultural activities:**  Upon visiting Yad Vashem facilities and/or registration for any of Yad Vashem’s educational and/or cultural activities, you may provide certain personal information, such as your name and contact details, and provide your consent to receive communications about Yad Vashem’s activities.  We require this information in order to provide you with various Services, to give you a response tailored to your specific requirements, and to enable ongoing communication to update you about Yad Vashem’s activities.  The information collected is also used for statistical purposes, in an anonymous manner and without any of your identifying details.   
* **Public Enquiries:**  Upon submission of an online enquiry and/or an enquiry via e-mail, you may provide us with certain personal information, such as your name and contact details, and the contents of your enquiry. We require this information in order to handle public enquiries, enhance and improve the Site and/or the Services, and enable us to respond to your enquiry.
* **Registration for Mailing Lists:** Upon your registration for mailing lists, you may provide us with certain personal information, such as your contact details and your preferences for receiving communications. We require this information in order to maintain ongoing communications with you, visitors, customers and/or donors of Yad Vashem, and in order to update you about Yad Vashem’s activities.
* **Purchases:** When making a purchase online and/or at Yad Vashem, you may provide us with specific personal information, such as your name, contact details, payment details, etc., for the purpose of processing such purchase and for accounting purposes.
* **Donations:**  Upon giving a donation to Yad Vashem, you may provide us with certain personal information such as your name, contact details, payment details, etc. We require this information in order to maintain ongoing communications with our donors, and for fundraising, reporting and accounting purposes (including issuing a receipt in accordance with the law). If you make a donation in US dollars you may be directed from our web-site to the websites of third-party service providers, including specifically [CauseMatch](https://www.causematch.com/privacy-policy/), PEF and [Stripe](https://stripe.com/privacy), where you may be asked to share certain information including your credit card details and contact information for the purposes of facilitating your donation. In such cases, in addition to this Privacy Policy, which shall apply to our use of your data, the service providers' terms of use and privacy policies shall also apply to their use of your data and you should review these closely.          
* **Photos:** We may photograph you at a Yad Vashem event (including educational activities) and/or at the time of your visit to Yad Vashem, in order to commemorate your visit and create a photo album of the visit, and for marketing purposes. In addition, there are security cameras activated 24/7 which may collect data such as photos of visitors for security purposes. We display appropriate notices to apprise you of the existence of such cameras at the site.
* **Participation in Surveys:** When you respond to a questionnaire and/or survey, or provide feedback to us, you may provide us with certain personal information about yourself as detailed in the questionnaire and/or survey.  This information is collected for research and/or marketing purposes.
* **Information Collected Automatically When Browsing the Site:**  The following personal information is automatically collected and saved for the purpose of enhancing the browsing experience and/or Services offered on the Site:          
* IP address from which you are connected to our Site.
* Name of your domain connected to the internet.
* Type of browser and operating system used to connect to our Site.
* Date and time you connected to our Site.
* Pages, files, documents and links you visited.
* Internet address which linked you to our Site.          

### Cookies

The Site uses cookies (hereinafter: “**Cookies**”).  Cookies are small data files sent to your computer upon visiting a specific site. Cookies are used to identify patterns of use, traffic trends, and consumer behavior, and to collect other information from an internet website.  On a repeat visit to the Site, Cookies enable the website to identify your server so that it will not be required to re-enter the same information the next time you visit the website. Cookies may contain information regarding the user’s preferences, activities on the website, and other details.

This Site uses Google Analytics, a product of Google (hereinafter: “**Google**”) which helps site owners to understand user interaction with their site.  Upon visiting the Site, the browser automatically sends certain information to Google through Cookies. This information includes, _inter alia,_ the internet address of the site you are visiting and the IP address; but Google will not collate the IP address with any other information that it holds.  The collected information is saved by Google and Google uses the information to evaluate usage of the Site, and to create activity reports for site managers. Google may also transfer the information to a third party when required to do so by law, or when a third party processes the information for Google.  Browsing this site constitutes your consent to collection of data by Google in the manner and for the uses listed above. For additional information on how to cancel information sharing with Google Analytics: [Find out more on how to opt out of Google Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en&ref_topic=2919631=2919631) and more information about [Google Analytics and safeguarding of your personal data](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en&ref_topic=2919631).

### Email Communications

We would like to send you e-mail communications, from time to time, about Yad Vashem’s activities which may be of interest to you. These communications will be sent only after you have provided consent to this and in accordance with the law. You may withdraw your consent and stop receiving such communications at any time, by clicking on the unsubscribe link that appears in each such email communication from us or by sending an e-mail to the site manager at [webmaster@yadvashem.org.il](mailto:webmaster@yadvashem.org.il).

### Data Protection of Minors

Yad Vashem safeguards the privacy of children and does not deliberately collect any personal information related to children.  Minors under the age of 18 are requested not to share personal information; however, if they wish to do so, they should obtain the consent of a parent or guardian before sending and/or sharing any personal information with the Site.  In the event that Yad Vashem has reasonable grounds to believe that parental consent has not been given, Yad Vashem will be entitled to refuse provision of any of its Services, at its sole discretion.

### Legal Basis for Processing

Yad Vashem will only collect, process and share personal information in accordance with the law and if there is a legal basis to do so, including for the purpose of fulfilling a contract (i.e., to provide services), furthering a legitimate interest of the organization and/or complying with a legal requirement. Where there is no other valid legal basis to collect, process and/or share personal information, we may collect your personal information only with your consent.  You may withdraw your consent at any time by written notice by e-mail. For the avoidance of doubt, withdrawal of your consent will not affect our right to continue to process personal information which you consented to prior to the withdrawal and/or other data processing that is being done on other lawful grounds.

### Retention of Information

Any personal information collected is retained by Yad Vashem in its databases. Personal information is stored in Israel or elsewhere subject to the Regulations of Protection of Privacy (Transfer of Information to Databases Outside the Boundaries of the State of Israel), 5761-2001, and any other applicable law, and in particular local data protection laws of the locality of the database.

Yad Vashem keeps your personal information for as long as necessary in order to fulfill the objectives set forth in this Privacy Policy or for a longer period if so required at its sole discretion. Yad Vashem reviews this periodically, in order to ensure that your personal information is not kept beyond the time required.

### Sharing Information with a Third Party

Yad Vashem keeps your personal information confidential and does not use your personal information other than for the purposes listed herein. Yad Vashem does not transfer your personal information to third parties, other than as follows:

* Transferring information to donors (for example, personal information of participants in educational activities may be transferred to entities which contributed to the funding of these activities);
* Transferring information to Yad Vashem’s partners, for the purpose of furthering its objectives, including local organizations of Yad Vashem worldwide;
* For the purpose of providing Services to you by means of and/or through the support of third parties (for example, when a program is operated by an external provider or in cooperation with another educational institution);
* As required in order to comply with legal or regulatory requirements and/or in the event of receipt of a judicial order requiring personal information to be forwarded to a third party;
* In accordance with the legitimate interests of Yad Vashem in fulfilling its mandate prescribed by law, and in particular the Holocaust Heroes and Remembrance Law - Yad Vashem 5713-1953;
* In the event of a legal dispute between you and Yad Vashem which requires disclosure of your personal information;
* As required in order to further the objectives of the Holocaust Heroes and Remembrance Law - Yad Vashem 5713-1953 (when providing testimony and/or personal information regarding the Holocaust, it is assumed that all such information is gathered and provided to enable Yad Vashem to perform its legal mandate and for the purpose of publication and sharing with the public, unless indicated otherwise at the time such information is collected/provided);
* As required in accordance with the Regulations for Protection of Privacy (Terms of securing information and its Transfer between Public Entities), 5746-1986.

When your personal information is transferred to third parties, we request these third-party entities to undertake to safeguard your information and to use it solely for the purposes for which it was provided.

### Security

Yad Vashem employs all technical and organizational measures necessary to ensure the appropriate level of security for your personal information. In addition, whenever we transfer or share your personal information to third parties in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy, we obligate such third parties to take equivalent technical and organizational measures necessary in order to protect your information.

Notwithstanding the above, transmission of information over the internet is not absolutely secure.  Therefore, Yad Vashem is unable to undertake that all of its servers are absolutely secure from unauthorized access. We will comply with applicable law with respect to breach of security of your personal information and will notify you of such as required under law.  Without derogating from our liability under law, Yad Vashem does not assume any responsibility whatsoever with respect to any breaches and/or theft of any personal information.

### Links to Third Party Sites

There may be links on Yad Vashem’s Site and/or in its advertisements to third party sites and/or resources which do not belong to Yad Vashem. When you click these third-party links, you leave our Site and your privacy will no longer be protected under this Privacy Policy. Use of any third-party links is at your own risk. When you make a donation in US dollars via our website, you may be redirected to the third party sites, including [Stripe](https://stripe.com/privacy) and/or PEF and/or [CauseMatch](https://www.causematch.com/privacy-policy/) and should review their privacy policies prior to the provision of personal data.

Yad Vashem is not responsible and has no control over the safeguarding of confidentiality and/or usage of information collected by such sites and/or the content of such sites, and inclusion of third-party links on the Site do not imply Yad Vashem’s approval of such sites and/or contents and/or their privacy policies. Yad Vashem does not undertake any liability in relation to the data collection, usage, sharing or any other action taken with respect to information collected by third party sites.  In any event where you click through to any third-party site, we recommend that you carefully review the terms of use and/or Privacy Policy of such site.

### Your Rights Regarding Your Personal Information

Under the Protection of Privacy Law, 5741-1981, every person is entitled to access his or her information stored in a database. If any information held is incorrect, incomplete, unclear or outdated, such person is entitled to request the amendment or deletion of such information. If you wish to contact Yad Vashem regarding personal information held by Yad Vashem, or to request the amendment or deletion of any personal information, you may contact Yad Vashem as per the contact details set forth below.

In addition, if any information in Yad Vashem’s database is used for email communication purposes, you are entitled to request in writing that such information be deleted from the database.

In instances where the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (GDPR) applies, you are entitled to certain rights pursuant to applicable law, including the right to receive information, the right to access the information, the right to amend the information and to delete it, the right to restrict the processing of the information, the right to move the information, the right to object to and refrain from receiving automatic decisions.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time.  We advise that you carefully read the Privacy Policy as it appears on the Site whenever you access the Site, to ensure that you are aware of steps taken by Yad Vashem to protect your privacy.

We will post a notice on the Site in the event that we make substantive changes to this Privacy Policy concerning usage of your personal information.  In addition, in the event of substantive changes, we will make every effort to inform you by means of customary communication methods, and if required under law – to receive your consent to the substantive changes with respect to use of your personal information.  Unless otherwise stated, all changes will take effect upon the date of publication on the Site. Your continued use of our Services after any updates to this Privacy Policy will be deemed as consent to the changes.  Details concerning the latest update of each version will appear at the end of the Privacy Policy.

### Law and Jurisdiction

The law of the State of Israel will apply to this Privacy Policy, without having regard to conflict of laws principles. The courts of the Jerusalem District, Israel will have sole and exclusive jurisdiction with regards to any dispute arising out of this Privacy Policy. 

### Contact us

If you wish to contact Yad Vashem with respect to any matter related to your personal information or protection of privacy, you can contact the Privacy Protection Officer by emailing [webmaster@yadvashem.org.il](mailto:webmaster@yadvashem.org.il) or by mailing as follows:

Yad Vashem – The Holocaust Martyrs’ and Heroes’ Remembrance Authority  
Privacy Protection Officer P.O. 3477, Jerusalem 9103401  
Tel: (972) 2 6443400  
Fax: (972) 2 6443569

**Latest update November 2023**

Online Store

To Bear Witness

$62.00

Yad Vashem. Moshe Safdie: The Architecture of Memory

$62.00

Yad Vashem  
Har Hazikaron  
P.O.B. 3477  
Jerusalem 9103401 Israel  

Fax: (972) 2 6443569  
Email: [webmaster@yadvashem.org.il](mailto:webmaster@yadvashem.org.il)

x

##### Subscription for e-Newsletter

Thank you for registering to receive information from Yad Vashem.

You will receive periodic updates regarding recent events, publications and new initiatives.

Useful Links

Suggested Resources

Digital Collections

Interested in receiving information and updates from Yad Vashem?

  Sign Up

 I agree to receive information about Yad Vashem's activities, courses, lectures and publications and direct mail from Yad Vashem, subject  
to Yad Vashem's Privacy Policy. It is possible to unsubscribe from the mailing list at any time.

Copyright © 2024 Yad Vashem. The World Holocaust Remembrance Center

"The work of Yad Vashem is critical and necessary to remind the world of the consequences of hate"

Paul Daly

#GivingTuesday  
Donate to Educate Against Hate

[DONATE NOW](https://forms.yadvashem.org/donation?utm_source=campaign-popup&utm_campaign=giving-tuesday) x

##### Interested in receiving information and updates from Yad Vashem?

 Are you interested in receiving information about Christian Friends of Yad Vashem?

  Sign up

Vast resources have been used to make these databases accessible.  
  
Your donation is vital to this continued endeavour.

Worldwide antisemitism is on the rise.

At Yad Vashem, we strive to make the world a better place by combating antisemitism through teacher training, international lectures and workshops and online courses.

We need you to partner with us in this vital mission to #EducateAgainstHate

[DONATE NOW](https://forms.yadvashem.org/donation?campaign_name=end-of-year-2019&utm_source=campaign-popup&utm_campaign=yearend-2019) x

x

#### New Yad Vashem website redirection

The good news:

The Yad Vashem website had recently undergone a major upgrade!

The less good news:

The page you are looking for has apparently been moved.

We are therefore redirecting you to what we hope will be a useful landing page.

For any questions/clarifications/problems, please contact: [webmaster@yadvashem.org.il](mailto:webmaster@yadvashem.org.il)

Press the X button to continue
